# WAEL ALMATTAR

# **FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Current address: Salmovska 10, Prague, Czech Republic waelsy123@gmail.com | +420 79 25 35 299 | +49 1525 1969 461

Freelancer - one person business - registered in Poland: Wael Almattar Systems ul. Sprzeczna 4/13 03-977 Warszawa NIP: 9512448547

VAT: PL 9512448547

-----

Highly motivated, pro-active and ambitious freelance Senior Software Engineer who is instinctively entrepreneurial. Agile evangelist. Strong personality and leadership abilities. Experienced in managing international and distributed teams. Open minded and bright with 6 years of experience in web development, performance optimization and architecture design. Lives and breathes software development.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Position**

Techloop.io Sep 2018 – present Prague, Czech Republic

#### Responsibilities:

- Working in agile environment.
- Working with the team to develop full stack with microservices third-party solutions
- Leading team of 5 great talents consists of Front-end & back-end and devops developers
- Consult the business team to draw a reliable road map
- Working closely with the analytics team to provide rich source of data
- Developing Front-end, backend and microservice apps written in Nodejs, Reactjs

Skills: node.js, git, react, antd, auth0, algolia, segment, material-ui, unit test, heroku workers, big data

### **JAVA-SCRIPT SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Blue Infinity S.R.O / International Red Cross ICRC March 2018 – Sep 2018

Prague - Zurich

### Responsibilities:

- Developing custom CRM platform for the international red cross, and a consultant at Blue Infinity.
- Using React.js, Redux,, Typescript, microsoft stack (teams ,TFS), Git extensions.

- Working closely with the client on finding the most suitable solutions.
- Leading a team of backend and frontend developers with Scrum meetings, PBI, and explain mock-ups..
- Unit testing and documentation.

# React.js Developer

Dether.io Jan 2018 – March 2018 Paris, France - remotely

### Responsibilities:

- Leading development an interactive map for users and clients
- Draw a development plan to keep the code well-organised and fully-tested including UI, load, unit, and end-to-end testing
- Full-stack development with React, Redux and Leaflet
- Key skills: Node.js, React, Leaflet, Redux-React, Heroku, lint, CircleCi

#### Lead SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Vari Solutions Oct 2017 – April 2018 (7 months) Greater New York City Area, USA - remotely

### Responsibilities:

- Working with the core team to grow the main product VariTest
- Development of API platform
- UI, load, unit, and end-to-end testing
- Full-stack implementation for the platform.
- **Key skills:** Node.js, Cache mem, postgresql, Angularjs, Travis, Heroku, Lint, chai, puppeteer.js, Locust,

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

GlobeIT

Warsaw, Poland

Mar 2016 to Sep 2017 (19 months)

### Responsibilities:

- Design a complete platform for GPS tracking devices with live real-time tracking using NodeJS, Socket.io and AngularJS.
- Create and design encoder/decoder server for handling GPS binary device's data and send commands.
- Optimize web application speed and data structures by combining Memory and Mysql databases.
- Lead API development of new eCommerce/Digital platform (PHP and Nodejs)
- Designed a dashboard and complete solution for chat module of eCommerce project using PHP and Angular S.
- Maintain existing eCommerce and Digital applications to meet the ever-evolving demands of the

business (PHP)

- Implemented online payment system for eCommerce services.
- Create from skratch an interactive Web Conference Video platform for creating video rooms with text and voice using WebRTC technology, socket.io and jQuery.
- Understanding of huge existing site.
- Used AngularJS as the development framework to build dashboard a single-page application and to create more interactive front end development.
- Developed a Web-Scraping web application with Entire server side application using Python.
- Formulated and documented technical architecture, components and strategies for mitigating technical challenges.
- Worked with the business to identify the API's, define data schema and document workflows.
- Design and develop Custom Components, workflows and templates.
- Used Git Version Management.
- This Web application is based on oauth2 based Authorization and Authentication.
  - Design & develop common platform frameworks on NodeJS. Ex:- logging, rest client, exception handling.
- Developed the Entire server side application using NodelS.
- Used Socket.io RESTful for web service by exchanging JSON data between the applications.
- Responsible for deploying code using Unix scripts.

#### Skills Used:

NodeJS, AngularJS, SOCKET.IO, ExpressJS, Redis, PHP, CSS, jQuery, Zend framework, MySQL, Python, WebRTC, loopback.

### WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

Mamania.pl Warsaw, Poland

July 2014 to September 2014

Implementing new features for online bookstore.

Skills Used:

Zend framework, PHP, MySQL, CSS

## **EDUCATION**

### **JOINT MASTER IN SPACE SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY:**

3rd semester | Université Toulouse III - Paul Sabatier Toulouse, France

Sep 2017 to April 2018

2nd semester | Lulea University of Technology Kiruna, Sweden

Feb 2017 to June 2017

1st semester | Julius-Maximilian's University Würzburg, Germany

Oct 2016 to Feb 2017

### **Bachelor in Computer Science, GPA 4.1**

Warsaw University of Technology Oct 2013 to Feb 2016 Warszawa, Poland

# **Bachelor in Computer Engineering and Automation**

Tishreen University to July 2013

Lattakia, Syria Sep 2010

# **AWARDS**

## 2010 - Bronze Medal - Syrian Olympiad in Informatics

competition requires solving problems of an algorithmic nature under time pressure.

# 2012 - 5th place - Syrian Collegiate Programming Contest

3 members teams contest requires solving problems of an algorithmic nature under time pressure.

### **LANGUAGES**:

English C1 - Arabic Native - Czech B1 - Polish B1 - German A2

### **HOBBIES**:

Skiing, Gymnastics, Chess, Piano, Swimming, Paragliding